Roger Steve Ruiz

+18045392255 hi@roq.qr http://roq.qr Richmond, VA & Remote

Profile

I'm a web developer with years of experience building websites, interfaces, & products. From concept to execution, I'm interested in all aspects of user experience, interface design, & code optimizations. I've worked with JetBlue, Caesars Casinos, WellPoint, Chipotle, Condé Nast, & other clients. I have a proven background in successfully handling all aspects of web development.

Experience

FRONT-END ENGINEER, CO+LAB MULTIMEDIA; RICHMOND, VA - 2015 - PRESENT

Optimizing front-end workflows & deployments on a team of seven developers. Building WordPress themes & customized installations. Extending the core functionality of WordPress by creating custom-APIs for bidirectional communications between the client and server.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER, CONDÉ NAST: NEW YORK, NY - 2013 - 2015

Building & maintaining a video streaming website along with nine other engineers. Practicing SCRUM along with continuous integration & daily deployments to production. Worked closely with the vice president of product design & engineering. Working in a completely Rails 4 development environment. Working remotely four to five times per month.

SENIOR DEVELOPER, ROKKAN: NEW YORK, NY - 2011 - 2013

Worked collaboratively with UI & UX designers to execute websites for clients. Involved in client presentations & internal meetings throughout the process. Lead developer on JetBlue, Chipotle, & WellPoint projects. Gave talks & trained coworkers on new topics.

Education

Nassau Community College 2007 – A.A.S. Digital Art & Printing

Skills

HTML, CSS, Sass, JavaScript, jQuery, Ember, Backbone, MVC, Ruby, Rails, AMD, TDD, Agile, NodeJS, Grunt, Gulp, Bash, Zsh, Git, SVN, /r[egx]{2,}p?/i, Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign

References available upon request